Twenty-eight years ago, I was a broken man.
منذ 28 عاماً مضت، كنت رجلاً محطماً.
And you probably wouldn't be able to tell that if you met me.
وربما لم تكن لتعرف ذلك إذا قابلتني.
I had a good job at a well-respected academic institution.
كان لدي عمل جيد في معهد أكاديمي محترم.
I dressed well, of course.
بالطبع، كان مظهري جيداً.
But my insides were rotting away.
ولكن دواخلي كانت محطمة.
You see, I grew up in a family riddled with addiction,
كما ترون، لقد تربيت في عائلة مليئة بالإدمان.
and as a kid, I also struggled
وكطفل، فقد عانيت كثيراً
with coming to terms with my own sexuality.
لفهم ميولي الجنسية.
And even though I couldn't name it then,
وبالرغم من أنني لم أكن أستطيع تحديدها حينها،
growing up as a gay kid
كان الترعرع كطفل مثلي جنسياً
just compounded my issues of isolation and insecurities.
سبباً في تفاقم مشاكلي مع العزلة وعدم الأمان.
But drinking took all of that away.
ولكن شرب الخمور أنساني كل ذلك.
Like many, I drank at an early age.
مثل الكثيرين، فقد بدأت الشرب في عمر مبكر.
I continued to drink my way through college.
واصلت الشرب أثناء دراستي في الكلية.
And when I finally did come out in the early 1980s,
وأخيراً عندما اعترفت بحقيقة ميولي الجنسية بدايات الثمانينات،
about the only places to meet other gay people,
كانت الأماكن الوحيدة المتاحة لأتعرف على المثليين الآخرين،
to socialize,
لأتأقلم،
to be yourself, were gay bars.
لأكون على طبيعتي، هي نوادي المثليين.
And what do you do in gay bars?
وماذا يمكنك فعله في تلك النوادي؟
You drink.
يمكنك الشرب.
And I did --
وقد فعلت ذلك...
a lot.
كثيراً.
My story is not unique.
قصتي ليست من القصص النادرة.
Like millions of Americans, my disease progressed undiagnosed.
كملايين الأمريكيين، تفاقمت حالتي المرضية بدون تشخيص.
It took me to people and places and things
لقد أخذني هذا المرض إلى أشخاص وأماكن أخرى
that I never would have chosen.
لم أكن لأختارها أبداً.
It wasn't until an intersection with the law
بقيت كذلك حتى اصطدمت بالقانون،
gave me an "opportunity" to get care,
مما أعطاني "فرصة" لتلقي الرعاية،
that I began my journey of recovery.
ثم بدأت رحلتي إلى الشفاء.
My journey of recovery has been filled with love and with joy,
كانت رحلتي إلى الشفاء مليئة بالحب والفرح،
but it hasn't been without pain.
ولكنها لم تخلُ من الألم أيضاً.
Like many of you, I've lost too many friends and family to this disease.
مثل الكثيرين منكم، فقد فقدت كثيراً من أصدقائي وعائلتي بسبب هذا المرض.
I've heard too many heartbreaking stories
لقد سمعت الكثير من القصص المؤلمة
of people who've lost loved ones to addiction.
عن أناس فقدوا أحباءهم بسبب الإدمان.
And I've also lost countless friends to HIV and AIDS.
فقدت عدداً لا يُحصى من الأصدقاء بسبب الإيدز.
Our current opioid epidemic and the AIDS epidemic
يتشابه وباؤنا الحالي ووباء الإيدز
tragically have much in common.
كثيراً، للأسف.
Right now, we are in the midst of one of the greatest health crises of our time.
الآن، نحن في منتصف أحد أسوأ الأزمات الصحية.
During 2014 alone, 28,000 people
خلال عام 2014 فقط، توفي 28,000 شخص
died of drug overdoses associated with prescription drugs and heroin.
بسبب جرعات المخدرات الزائدة المصاحبة لوصفات الدواء الطبية والهيروين.
During the 1980s, scores of people were dying from HIV and AIDS.
خلال الثمانينات، زاد معدل الوفاة بسبب الإيدز.
Public officials ignored it.
لقد تجاهل المسؤولون ذلك الأمر.
Some wouldn't even utter the words.
بعضهم لم ينطق بكلمةٍ واحدة.
They didn't want treatment.
لم يرغبوا في العلاج.
And tragically, there are many parallels with our current epidemic.
وللأسف، هناك تشابهٌ كبيرٌ مع وضعنا الحالي.
Some called it the gay plague.
بعضهم يدعون الأمر بمأساة المثليين.
They called for quarantines.
إنهم ينادون بعمل حجر صحي.
They wanted to separate the innocent victims from the rest of us.
يريدون أن يفصلوا الضحايا الأبرياء عن بقيتنا.
I was afraid we were losing this battle
كنت أخشى أننا سنخسر المعركة.
because people were blaming us for being sick.
لأن الناس كانوا يلوموننا لأننا مرضى.
Public policy was being held hostage by stigma and fear,
كانت السياسة العامة مقيدة بالخوف ووصمة العار.
and also held hostage
وكذلك كان
were compassion, care, research, recovery and treatment.
التعاطف، والرعاية، والأبحاث، والشفاء، والعلاج.
But we changed all that.
ولكننا غيرنا كل ذلك.
Because out of the pain of those deaths,
لأنه من خلال كل الألم الذي سببته كل هذه الوفيات،
we saw a social and political movement.
رأينا حركةً اجتماعيةً وسياسية.
AIDS galvanized us into action;
لقد ساعدنا الإيدز على التحرك.
to stand up, to speak up and to act out.
لنقف، لنتكلم ولنفعل.
And it also galvanized the LGBT movement.
كما ساعد أيضًا على إنشاء حركة المثليين.
We knew we were in a battle for our lives
لقد أدركنا أننا في معركة لإنقاذ أنفسنا
because silence equaled death,
لأن الصمت كان يعني الموت،
but we changed, and we made things happen.
ولكننا تغيرنا، وجعلنا الأمور تحدث.
And right now, we have the potential
والآن، نرى احتمال
to see the end of HIV/AIDS in our lifetime.
نهاية مرض الإيدز قريباً.
These changes came in no small part
حدثت هذه التغيرات بسبب
by the courageous, yet simple decision
القرار السليم والشجاع
for people to come out
الذي أخذه الناس لكي يصارحوا
to their neighbors, to their friends, to their families
جيرانهم، أصدقائهم، عائلاتهم
and to their coworkers.
وزملائهم في العمل.
Years ago, I was a volunteer for the Names Project.
قبل سنوات، كنت متطوعًا في مشروع أسماء "Names".
This was an effort started by Cleve Jones in San Francisco
هذا الجهد بذله في البداية (كليف جونز) في سان فرانسيسكو.
to show that people who died of AIDS
كي يثبت بأن الناس الذين ماتوا بسبب الإيدز
had names
لديهم أسماء
and faces and families
ووجوه وأسر
and people who loved them.
والناس الذين كانوا يحبونهم.
I still recall unfolding the AIDS memorial quilt
ولا زلت أتذكر مأساة الإيدز
on the National Mall on a brilliant day in October, 1988.
في المركز الوطني في يوم جميل من أكتوبر 1988.
So fast forward to 2015.
بسرعة وصولاً للعام 2015.
The Supreme Court's decision to strike down the ban on same-sex marriage.
قرار المحكمة العليا لفك حظر زواج المثليين
My husband, Dave, and I walk over to the steps of the Supreme Court
ذهبت أنا وزوجي ديف إلى المحكمة العليا
to celebrate that decision with so many other people,
لنحتفل بذلك القرار، مع أناس آخرين مثلنا،
and I couldn't help but think how far we came around LGBT rights
لم أكن أستطيع التذكر بوضوح ولكن تذكرت كم كنا بعيدين والآن اقتربنا
and yet how far we needed to go around issues of addiction.
ورغم ذلك، مازال علينا الذهاب لأقصى مدى بمشاكل الإدمان
When I was nominated by President Obama
عندما تم ترشيحي من قبل الرئيس (أوباما)
to be his Director of Drug Policy,
لأصبح رئيس حملته ضد المخدرات
I was very open about my recovery and about the fact that I was a gay man.
كنت منفتحاً تجاه تجربتي لإعادة التأهيل وكوني رجلاً مثليّاً.
And at no point during my confirmation process --
وفي لحظة غير معروفة أثناء تلك التجربة الانفتاحية
at least that I know of --
على الأقل ما أنا متأكدٌ منه...
did the fact that I was a gay man come to bear on my candidacy
هل تأتي حقيقة كوني رجلاً مثلياًّ بتأثير ما على ترشحي
or my fitness to do this job.
أم يؤثر على مقدرتي لأداء تلك الوظيفة
But my addiction did.
لكن إدماني حسم الأمر.
At one point, a congressional staffer said that there was no way
وفي نقطة معينة، قال أحد أعضاء الكونغرس، أنه لا توجد طريقة
that I was going to be confirmed by the United States Senate
لقبولي من قبل مجلس الشيوخ الأمريكي
because of my past,
وذلك بسبب تاريخي مع الإدمان.
despite the fact that I had been in recovery for over 20 years,
بالرغم من حقيقة أنني تعافيت منذ ما يزيد عن 20 عام،
and despite the fact
وبالرغم من حقيقة
that this job takes a little bit of knowledge around addiction.
أن هذه الوظيفة تحتاج لمعرفة قليلة بالإدمان.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So, you know, this is the stigma
حسنا، وكما تعلمون، تلك كانت وصمة عار
that people with substance use disorders
للناس الذين يواجهون الاضطرابات
face every single day,
التي تواجههم كل يوم
and you know, I have to tell you
وكما تعلمون، سأخبركم بذلك
it's still why I'm more comfortable coming out as a gay man
ما يزال السبب في أنني أكثر راحةً في التعريف بنفسي كرجلٍ مثلي
than I am as a person with a history of addiction.
عن التعريف بأنني شخص ذو تاريخٍ مع الإدمان
Nearly every family in America is affected by addiction.
الأسر الأمريكية تأثرت وتعاني معظمها من الإدمان
Yet, unfortunately, too often, it's not talked about openly and honestly.
ورغم ذلك، ويا للأسف، فإنه غالباً لا يتم الحديث عن ذلك بإنفتاحية وأمانة .
It's whispered about.
ما زالوا يتهامسون بذلك.
It's met with derision and scorn.
ومازال الموضوع يُقابل بالسخرية والإزدراء
We hear these stories, time and time again, on TV, online,
لقد سمعنا بتلك القصص مرة تلو الأخرى، من خلال التلفاز، الإنترنت،
we hear it from public officials, and we hear it from family and friends.
لقد سمعنا بها من موظفيين عموميين، كما سمعنا بها من العائلة والأصدقاء
And those of us with an addiction, we hear those voices,
وكذلك المدمنون منا، سمعنا جميع تلك الأصوات
and somehow we believe that we are less deserving of care and treatment.
ولا أدري كيف ولكننا آمنا بأننا نستحق القليل من الرعاية وإعادة التأهيل.
Today in the United States, only one in nine people
والآن، يوجد بالولايات المتحدة الأمريكية واحد من بين كل تسعة
get care and treatment for their disorder.
ممن يتلقون العناية والعلاج لاضطرابهم
One in nine.
واحد من بين كل تسعة.
Think about that.
فكروا في ذلك.
Generally, people with other diseases get care and treatment.
عموماً، فإن أناس آخرين يتلقون الرعاية والعلاج لأمراض أخرى
If you have cancer, you get treatment,
فإن كنت مصاباً. بالسرطان فإنك تتلقى العلاج
if you have diabetes, you get treatment.
إذا كنت مصاباً بالسكري،
If you have a heart attack,
وإذا أصبت بنوبةٍ قلبية
you get emergency services, and you get referred to care.
تتلقى علاج الطوارئ ومن ثم يتم تحويلك للعناية
But somehow people with addiction have to wait for treatment
ولكن ولسبب ما، فإن المصابين بالإدمان عليهم الإنتظار لتلقي العلاج
or often can't get when they need it.
وأحيانا لا يستطيعون تلقي العلاج حين الحاجة.
And left untreated, addiction has significant, dire consequences.
وفي حالة عدم معالجة الإدمان، فإن له عواقب وخيمة وضخمة
And for many people that means death or incarceration.
وللعديد من الناس فإن ذلك يعني الموت أو السجن
We've been down that road before.
لقد خضنا ذلك الطريق من قبل
For too long our country felt
ولوقت طويل شعرت بلادنا
like we could arrest our way out of this problem.
أننا نستطيع إيجاد طريقة للخروج من هذه المشكلة.
But we know that we can't.
ولكننا نعلم أننا لا نستطيع.
Decades of scientific research has shown
عقودٌ من البحث العلمي أظهرت
that this is a medical issue --
أن الإدمان مشكلةٌ طبية
that this is a chronic medical condition
وأنه مرضٌ مزمن
that people inherit and that people develop.
يرثه بعض الناس ويكتسبه البعض الآخر.
So the Obama administration has taken a different tack on drug policy.
ولذلك فإن إدارة (أوباما) اتخذت سياسةً مختلفةً للتعامل مع المخدرات
We've developed and implemented a comprehensive plan
فقد طورنا ونفذنا خطة شاملة
to expand prevention services, treatment services,
لتوسيع خدمات الوقاية والعلاج،
early intervention and recovery support.
وكذلك التدخل المبكر وتقديم الدعم خلال إعادة التأهيل.
We've pushed criminal justice reform.
وكما دفعنا بالعدالة الجنائية للأفضل.
We've knocked down barriers to give people second chances.
ولقد قمنا بإسقاط الحواجز لمنح الناس فرصة ثانية.
We see public health and public safety officials working hand in hand
لقد رأينا العاملين بقطاعي الصحة العامة والأمن العام يعملون يداً بيد.
at the community level.
على مستوى المجتمع.
We see police chiefs across the country guiding people to treatment
لقد رأينا رؤساء الشرطة عبر البلاد يرشدون الناس خلال رحلة العلاج.
instead of jail and incarceration.
بدلاً عن سجنهم وحجزهم.
We see law enforcement and other first responders
رأينا القانون ينفذ والآخرين يستجيبون للمرة الأولى
reversing overdoses with naloxone to give people a second chance for care.
وعكس الجرعة الزائدة لعقار (ناكسالون) لمنح الناس فرصةً ثانيةً للحصول على الرعاية
The Affordable Care Act is the biggest expansion
وسن قانون للرعاية بأسعار معقولة كان أكبر توسع
of substance use disorder treatment in a generation,
في علاج استخدام المواد المخدرة منذ جيل،
and it also calls for the integration of treatment services within primary care.
وتدعو أيضاً لإدماج خدمات العلاج ضمن الرعاية الأولية.
But fundamentally, all of this work is not enough.
ولكن في الأساس، كل هذا العمل لن يكفي.
Unless we change the way that we view people with addiction
ما لم نغير وجهة نظر الناس تجاه الإدمان
in the United States.
في الولايات المتحدة.
Years ago when I finally understood that I had a problem
منذ سنوات مضت، عندما أدركت أخيراً أنني أعاني من مشكلة
and I knew that I needed help,
وعلمت أيضاً أنني أحتاج للمساعدة،
I was too afraid to ask for it.
كنت خائفاً جداً من طلبها.
I felt that people would think I was stupid, that I was weak-willed,
إذ اعتقدت أن الناس سيعتبرونني غبياً، وصاحب عزيمةٍ ضعيفة،
that I was morally flawed.
بسبب عيبٍ أخلاقيٍ لدي من وجهة نظرهم.
But I talk about my recovery because I want to make change.
ولكنني تحدثت عن تعافيَّ لأنني أريد إحداث تغيير.
I want us to see that we need to be open and candid about who we are
أريدنا أن نرى أننا بحاجة للانفتاح وأن نصرِّح بهوياتنا
and what we can do.
وما الذي نستطيع فعله.
I am public about my own recovery
أنا أصرح وأشارك قصة تعافيَّ
not to be self-congratulatory.
ليس للتباهي أو تهنئة الذات.
I am open about my own recovery to change public opinion,
أنا أصرّح بقصة تعافيَّ للعامة لتغيير رأيهم
to change public policy
لتغيير السياسة العامة
and to change the course of this epidemic and empower the millions of Americans
ولإنهاء فصل هذا الوباء، ولإلهام ملايين الأمريكيين
who struggle with this journey
الذين يعانون خلال هذه الرحلة
to be open and candid about who they are.
ليكونوا منفتحين وصريحين حول هوياتهم.
People are more than their disease.
الناس أكثر من أمراضهم.
And all of us have the opportunity to change public opinion
وجميعنا لديه الفرصة لتغيير الرأي العام،
and to change public policy.
ولتغيير السياسة العامة.
All of us know someone who has an addiction,
جميعنا يعرف شخصاً ما يعاني من الإدمان،
and all of us can do our part
وجميعنا يستطيع المساهمة
to change how we view people with addiction in the United States.
بتغيير الرؤية ونظرة المجتمع للإدمان بالولايات المتحدة الأمريكية.
So when you see someone with an addiction,
ولذلك عندما ترى شخصاً مصاباً بالإدمان،
don't think of a drunk or a junkie or an addict or an abuser --
لا تفكر في أنه سكير أو منبوذ أو أنه مدمنٍ أو معتدي
see a person;
انظر للشخص على أنه إنسان
offer them help;
وقدِّم له المساعدة
give them kindness and compassion.
امنحه اللطف والتشجيع.
And together, we can be part
ومع بعضنا البعض يمكننا أن نكون جزءاً
of a growing movement in the United States
من الحركةٍ المتصاعدة داخل الولايات المتحدة
to change how we view people with addiction.
لتغيير وجهة النظر حول الإدمان.
Together we can change public policy.
مع بعضنا البعض يمكننا أن نغير السياسة العامة.
We can ensure that people get care when they need it,
يمكن أن نؤكد بأن الناس سيحصلون على الرعاية عندما يحتاجونها،
just like any other disease.
كأي مرض آخر.
We can be part of a growing, unstoppable movement
يمكن أن نكون جزءاً من الحركة المستمرة
to have millions of Americans enter recovery,
لدعم الكثير من الأمريكيين للتعافي،
and put an end to this epidemic.
ولوضع نهاية لهذا الوباء.
Thank you very much.
شكراً جزيلاً لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)